Tyler Young Senior Technical Writer

Website: tyler-young.com Email: tyler@tyler-young.com Phone: (360) 601-4398

A veteran Technical Writer with over 9 years of experience in crafting user-friendly technical instructions for all skill levels. My goal is to use my documentation writing expertise, technical knowledge, and customer support experience as part of a growing team focused on customer success.

Experience

Senior Product Documentation Specialist

May 2022 - March 2023

Nucleus Security

- Head of Documentation department. Responsible for all customer-facing documentation, including instructions for integrating with dozens of third-party services.
- Maintained and improved the documentation website itself, built using Document360, including implementing custom JavaScript to add additional features.
- Worked closely with product, marketing, and sales to support the definition and release of multiple features.
- Created roadmap for Documentation department and spearheaded a plan to bring all documentation up to WCAG2AA accessibility standards.

Technical Writer October 2020 – April 2022

Fastly

- Responsible for all customer-facing documentation related to security products, including web application and API protection, bot protection, edge-based WAF, and other cloud security features.
- Maintained and improved multiple documentation websites built with Hugo and Jekyll on AWS and GCS, adhering to WCAG2AA accessibility standards.
- Created training curriculum and instructed new team members in the use and troubleshooting of company security products.

Support Engineer

February 2018 - October 2020

Signal Sciences (acquired by Fastly)

- Head of Documentation department. Created and maintained all customer-facing documentation.
- Defined roadmap for Documentation department. Lead initiatives to improve documentation and processes.
- Managed and defined technical support for enterprise and SMB customers.
- Maintained documentation website built with Hugo on AWS, including deploying structural improvements.
- Created training curriculum and instructed new team members in the use and troubleshooting of products.
- Owned company status page and was responsible for managing incidents and public messaging.

Customer Support Agent III

January 2014 – July 2017

Media Temple (acquired by GoDaddy)

- Maintained and updated knowledge base documentation across all products.
- Wrote widely-adopted instructions and scripts for many common customer problems.
- Diagnosed and resolved issues with LAMP servers, databases, website development, email.
- Resolved thousands of customer tickets with a customer satisfaction rating of over 95%.

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology Willamette University June 2013

Writing Samples

https://tyler-young.com/tyler-young-writing-samples.pdf

Skills

Technical writing, documentation management, information security, SaaS, JIRA, Git, Markdown, DITA, HTML, CSS, WCAG, Docker, Google Analytics, Adobe Creative Cloud, AWS, Linux, web hosting, C#, Python, JavaScript